Register to the Tomasz Potworowski papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Tomasz Potworowski,
1937-2006
96060
Potworowski, Tomasz, 1924-
6 manuscript boxes (2.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Memoirs, correspondence, and military and identification documents, relating to Polish military training in Great Britain and subsequent military operations in France, Belgium and the Netherlands during World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1996.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Corporal, Polish army.
Scope and Content of Collection
Memoirs, correspondence, and military and identification documents, relating to Polish military training in Great Britain and subsequent military operations in France, Belgium and the Netherlands during World War II.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Poland. Polskie Siły Zbrojne.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Western Front.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.
Related Materials
Gustaw Potworowski papers (father), Hoover Institution Archives
Collection Contents
- "The Polish Legation's undiplomatic activities, Stockholm, September 1939-July 1942," by Tomasz Potworowski, reprinted from Acta Sueco-Polonica, Nr 10/11 (2001-2002), Uppsala Universitet, Uppsala, 2003 (Box 1)
- Army Days, 1943-1945. Recollection and reflections of a Polish soldier in the West at the time of Katyn, the Warsaw Uprising and Yalta, by Tomasz Potworowski. Second Printing, 1997 (Box 1)
- Army Days letters
  - Learning the trade, 1943 (Folder 1: 1)
  - The wait, 1944 (Folder 1: 2)
  - The Battle of Normandy, 1944 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Flanders, 1944 (Folder 1: 4)
  - North Brabant, 1944 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Yalta and after, 1945 (Folder 1: 6)
  - The end of hope, 1945 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Civvy street, 1945 (Folder 1: 8)
- Documents relating to Tomasz Potworowski Army Service, circa 1943-1945 (Folder 1: 9)
- Clippings, notes and correspondence about research, circa 1992-1994. (Folder 1: 10)
  Includes biographical information on Gustaw Potworowski and a photographic negative.
- Incremental Materials (Box 2-6:)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.